Last year I did over $100,000 in payouts
whilst doing this.
>> If you end up applying this model
correctly and waiting for the higher
probable ones, the win rate is
incredible to say the least. And that's
when the RR can get stupid. You don't
even need to look at the chart. The
hardest part for people is literally
just this guy is the world's best
liquidity trap trader with over $500,000
in payouts and close to $800,000 views
on his last Chart fanatics episode. If
you don't see liquidity, you are the
liquidity. I never like to predict where
liquidity is going to be. Hydrolos. I
simply let the market communicate that
to me. Again, what do I mean by that is
understanding. On this episode, he
reveals his universal trading da Vinci
model. No matter if you trade gold or
NASDAQ, S&P or Euro USD, this strategy
works. Here's your common retail
mistake. Low taken, high taken. There's
their VOS. Where do they want to be
buying from? Once you guys learn to cut
these kind of trades out of your plan,
you'll avoid a lot of losses. This is
literally a Da Vinci happening on the
higher time frames and then a Da Vinci
happening on the lower time frames. This
is like textbook style. Beautiful. Not
only does Mark go through it step by
step, but he also trades live every week
on chart fanatics live. Typically what
happens is you'll just get a pullback
and a continuation. Boom. Trade
invalidated. The novice trader or the
amateur trader is going to think there's
highs and highs and lows all over my
chart. What do I do? Right? Am I going
to sell above this, buy below this? It's
best in my opinion to literally just
Welcome back everyone to Chart Fanatics,
the go-to channel for all of your very
best strategy and concept breakdowns
with some of the very best traders in
the world. Today we actually have a
returning guest. His last episode did
600,000
views and climbing to this day. One of
the first people to trade live and do
live trading segments on Chartanax. He
actually trades live on Chart Fanatics
Live. And it's the one and only Marco
Aset.
Mark Shottny Marco Trades. I liked it.
Thanks for the intro.
>> I just doxed your name.
>> Gay. My full name is out there now.
Yeah, but I appreciate it, bro. I'm
excited to do this. Um, ever since you
hit me up and said, "Let's do a part
two." I've been like, "Yo, let's do it.
It's a good time." Well, today we're
going to go through the universal model
that you specifically absolutely crush
gold with. Uh, high riskreward, high win
rate, but if I'm not mistaken, this
works on any time frame and any asset.
Yeah. Yeah, 100%. So, this is going to
be we're going to be tapping into a
model I called the Da Vinci model. Um, I
kind of just threw a title on it just so
when I ever I take trades on it, I just
title it Da Vinci. Um, but yeah, like
you said, all markets, uh, that's the
beauty about this. And of course, it is
fractal to all time frames. That's
something I preach about is everything
that happens on the higher time frames
goes all the way down to the lower. So
sometimes this model is literally
playing out on the daily time frame, for
example, and then sometimes it's playing
out all the way down to the 1 minute. So
the easy thing about it um, to follow
and grasp is again it's it's frapple
from high to low, low to high, right?
about it.
>> And not only that, we're going to go
through it step by step exactly how this
presents itself, what to look for with
chart examples as well of many, many
trades that you've taken. And then just
to top it off, we'll add in a live
trading segment on top as well. I love
it. Yeah. We'll tap into a lot of stuff.
We got a lot coming. Also, didn't want
to mention any people here that are new,
we have the previous video. I thought
they should definitely watch because we
cover the foundations of liquidity, how
I view the market. Um, but again, it's
important to watch that video in order
to understand the model that we're going
to go through in this video. So, I just
wanted to mention that first so we can
avoid as much confusion as possible.
>> We'll have that linked either on screen
or in the description. So, if you don't
understand liquidity at its core, uh,
then check that out. But this now is
going into the specific entry and exit
criteria that Marco uses. So, where
should we begin?
>> We're going to try to make it a
step-by-step process as much as
possible. Um but there is core and
important um things I look for in order
to apply this model. Um so we're going
to start off at this guy here. So rough
idea is first again if you guys are new
here you'll understand that I would view
this high to have liquidity in the
market. Okay. And then if the market
sold off and let's just say we grabbed
something from the left hand side aka an
old low or we tapped into something um
and now we want to see bullish moves
back up to the upside. Okay. And again
we have a target up here this high. Um
now the model that I use again it's
called the Da Vinci model. Um the
important aspect uh the Da Vinci model
is you want to identify what I call
engineered liquidity. So in other words
um in this example where this is a
bullish scenario we want to see sellers
enter the market. Okay. So what do I
mean by that? Um, so just to make this
as easy as possible, we won't go into
the full Molly yet, but we'll talk about
this specific step that's very
important. So use the bed marker here.
Once price comes up here and we start
creating this high, again understand
that overall we want to see price up to
the upside. Okay, we have a level of
liquidity we want price to target. Now
what's happening here is when we travel
to the upside okay when we're coming
into this level of liquidity again that
we want to see ran eventually look how
we are respecting it printing this high
and then the market starts to retrace
now this is what I call
try and write as best as possible here
engineered liquidity okay again in other
words it's just um in this bullish
scenario this is sellers entering the
market here now um We spoke about it
again in the previous episode, but just
to touch on it, I never like to predict
where liquidity is going to be, highs or
lows. I simply let the market
communicate that to me. So again, what
do I mean by that? Very important. This
high here, respecting highs to the left
hand side, this is the market telling me
that we are building liquidity. And
let's even just put a
little dollar sign up here. We are
building liquidity. Okay, orders above
this high up here once we engineer
liquidity. Okay, so then typically what
happens? Sellers enter up here and the
market will retrace. Now, typically I
want to be buying down here. Okay, so
entry
would be down here. We're going to tap
into all this in depth. My entry would
be here and then we're we're going to
look for that move back out to the
upside. But the first and the most
important step to this model is
understanding engineer liquidity. And
this is this right here. Okay, so again
this is a bullish scenario. You guys can
literally just invert this and flip it
to look at a bearish scenario. But
again, the most important part to this
model. If you don't see engineered
liquidity, it's not a da Vinci model.
Okay. So that you say as well the power
of this model and the whole concept as a
whole is this is what will stop people
getting stopped out unnecessarily
getting caught in the wrong side of the
market and almost the market tricking
them to a degree because you can
identify now engineered liquidity and
identify what the market's actually
trying to do.
>> Yeah, exactly. And like I was talking
about before, we're simply we're
actually not even predicting what highs
and lows need to go. We're letting the
market literally, excuse me, we're
letting the market communicate to us by
printing this high up here, this
engineered liquidity high. We're letting
the market communicate to us that we are
going to go back higher, but the sellers
literally are going to enter here, build
that liquidity, give that reason, that
logic for price to move higher. And then
again, we're going to look for those
entries down here. And then when it
comes to entry, no doubt we're going to
go step by step into some of it. But
just at this point, are we entering
directly from here or is are you going
to look for something further?
>> Yeah. So this there's a couple we're
going to dive into entries on the
whiteboard. We'll talk about it more so
you guys understand. And then of course
in the charts uh but there's multiple
ways on taking this entry. Again the the
most important step and I need you guys
to just understand this as a whole
before we move forward is this engineer
liquidity point. Seeing this reaction
occur is the most important part. Once
we engineer liquidity now the model is
active and you can start looking for
entries right back to the upside. And
would you say because of the way the
model's presented and that engineered
liquidity is that what creates such a
high risk-to-reward and high win rate?
>> Yeah. Yeah, of course. So the thing is a
lot of people let's just say for example
um people are buying in this leg all the
way to the upside wherever and like
let's just say this is a higher time
frame. People are looking for lower time
entries on this bullish leg from low to
high. Now what happens is they want to
see price back up to these highs. So
price will come up and then it respects
and engineers and then comes back and
takes them all out, right? Anybody that
was buying here, they're taken out.
Anybody that was buying here, they're
taken out and then they'll take them all
out and then it'll move bullish. So yes,
the the beauty about this model is when
it comes to the extreme, the
risk-to-reward is just ridiculous.
Sometimes I'm talking like 1 to 10 plus.
Now, does this happen? We have to be
realistic. Does this happen all the
time? Doesn't happen all the time.
However, these are this is the reality
of the model and they do come along.
Sometimes they'll come along a couple
times in a week, sometimes once or twice
in a month, right? You just got to take
it for what it is.
>> And that's what in regards to that,
that's the high risk-to-reward, you
know, the bigger trades you're talking
about. But this model presents itself
very frequently, right, on a day-to-day
basis.
>> Yeah. Yeah. 100%. Like I said, it it
starts from the higher time frames. It's
fractal to the lower. So you see this
time frame or sorry you see this model
playing out on the higher and then if
you go down to the lower time frames of
course you you could see maybe the model
coming a couple times per day right if
you have a couple different assets on
the list.
Okay. So now we'll talk about
um how to basically take advantage of
the model and actually enter the market,
right? So again um and you know what,
we'll actually touch on an extreme
example to show you guys the the high RR
that can come along with this system.
Okay, so um let's just draw it up like
this.
Okay, so just like this piece of price
action we've talked about on the flip
side, right? We have highs intact up
here, level of liquidity. Now it's going
to start happening down here at the
lows. So high is taken this low
respecting this low and boom we have
built liquidity once sorry wait once we
move away boom now we built liquidity.
So now you have liquidity below this
low. So if you guys literally just look
at it again if you just invert it. Look
at the top. It's the exact same you can
call it a pattern. It's the exact same
logic just on the flip side. This is a
bullish level of liquidity and you have
sellers up there. Okay? So it's just the
same one that flips side. Now price
moves up to the upside and remember we
come up to the highs and this is where
we view sellers to be entering the
market. You want to see engineer
liquidity. So what happens is we print
this. Let's just keep it black for now.
So we come up and we go bearish. Okay.
So again this would be your
engineered liquidity. Okay. that high
right there. And we can also just draw
it on like this. We can say sellers are
entering
from an area on the left hand side.
Okay. And again, if you guys aren't new
here, previous video, this would just be
a PO, a POI of some sort of a retail, an
order block, whatever it is. Um, all we
can understand is though this high here
has been respecting highs on the left
hand side. So, it is engineering
liquidity. Okay, the first step to the
model basically you want to see the
engineer liquidity. Now the model's
active and we want to start looking for
entries. Now you're going to ask me,
okay, Marco, we understand that junior
liquidity. How do we take advantage? How
do we actually enter the market right
and target these highs? Trading
education is completely broken. For
years, the industry has been purged and
poisoned by bad actors, fake results,
and strategies hidden behind pay walls.
But in every industry, every once in a
while becomes a catalyst, a moment in
time for change. Now imagine a world
where elite trading education was
entirely free. Education with no hidden
agenda, verified trading results, and
real profitable strategies, all for
free. Welcome to Chart Academy.
Chart Academy is the world's first
all-in-one platform for trading
education. Chart Academy is free. No
catch, no upsells, no strings attached.
Worldclass trading education completely
free. Hi, my name is Randy Howell and
welcome to my Chart Academy Master
Class.
>> This is completely revolutionary, the
biggest change in trader education in 20
years.
>> My name is Karma Rosado. I'm a verified
7igure trader. I've been trading for 10
years now. The reason why a lot of trade
does fail is because they ultimately
this work is about selfmastery. Trading
education will never be the same again.
>> Browse hundreds of hours of content in
forex, futures, stock, options, and
crypto from the best verified traders on
the planet, all in one platform.
Experience a completely personalized
trading plan tailored to you and your
goals. Reach milestones, redeem points,
and earn rewards with a massive global
community. Whether you trade forex,
futures, stock, options, or crypto,
Chart Academy has something for you.
Join the weight list now and be part of
a movement that is going to change
trading education forever.
Now, look what I've drawn on down here
at the low. We have high, low, high,
low, and we move bullish to the upside.
Okay? Leaving a level of liquidity to
the downside. Now what happens is
typically uninformed traders and let me
just uh hopefully we can fit this here.
People will start looking for buys down
here. Okay, look you have high taken. So
any retail traders um trading off
structure Fibonacci whatever it is
usually will be entering in some sort of
areas in here.
Okay, they want to be taking buys, but
we understand we want to buy below lows,
sell above highs.
We want to see price typically what
happens is you get a little false
reaction and then price comes down to
the low. Boom. As soon as, and this is
very important right here, guys. Um, a
lot of people like to kind of, and I
call it overrefine and look for an
imbalance in this low. In my opinion,
unnecessary. This is providing you in a
very high RR. You don't need to
overrefini because typically when people
overrefini you're going to start missing
entries. So to keep it as easy as
possible and that's I preach this on
daily basis to keep this as easy as
possible once this low right here is
taken where the liquidity is you enter
your buy position. So buy will basically
be right there. So that's where we're
entering a buy position. Typically what
happens afterwards of course is the
price will move all the way to the
upside. Okay. So like with this concept,
there's multiple levels to it, right? So
when once this has been swept Yes. to
the low essentially
this brings in your sense. Yes. So then
people are going to be entering sells
all along here. It's already taken out
buyers at this point. Yeah. Cuz it's
taking a significant load to the ring
below and all low to the left. So it's
already taken out the buyers from that
position, if you will. This then entices
the sellers. This then
uh also entices some buying here.
>> Yep.
>> Right. And when we get to here, more
sellers still stacked. So then we're
having this reaction and stacks even
more here. Yep. Price then comes back
down again. To your point, there'll be
buyers trying to buy because of this
structure. Yep. And then once price
reacts and breaks that low, more sellers
probably here, more sellers trying to
sell here. Yep. when in reality at this
point all buyers have been taken out and
all that's left is the highs.
>> Exactly. Exactly. So the the hardest and
I don't even want want to say hard
hardest part because people need
patience in every single strategy in
every single system out there but the
the variable that people struggle with
the most is just waiting for the setup
to occur, right? waiting for these lows
down here to get taken because per the
model, per the da Vinci model, remember
this can provide if you wait and you
stay patient, this can provide you
ridiculous RR and a ridiculous win rate
sometimes. So if you just learn how to
wait, you learn how to trust the level
of liquidity here. Once that low is
taken right there, that is your entry.
And just to make this as easy again,
entry here and stop loss is going to be
below this low. So this is your stop
loss down here. your stop loss is going
to cover this low from the lefth hand
side. So look, entry, stop loss, very
tight risk. And look at the gain on the
table. Um, if we could just use the
blue, you have from entry all the way up
to target, which would be this high.
Think about it, where is the liquidity?
Ask yourself, you have this high
respecting all these highs from the
lefth hand side. You want to be
targeting that liquidity, right? Because
let's just say we do end up moving
bearish. We shouldn't move bearish until
this high is taken, right? And again,
you have all of this gain on the table
for look how much risk. Very small, very
small risk. I would say this is the most
simple way of trading uh and
understanding what's going on behind the
candles and the general positioning
within the market without having to get
really complex with orderflow. Right?
I'm sure orderflow uh could give some
more insights but then equally there
comes that it's really interesting when
it comes to complexity because people
say that you know once you understand
all of those it's not as complex
actually very simple uh but this is a
really amazing way of you're you're
taking that concept basically but
presenting it using the candlesticks and
really you're just I know people might
not like to hear it but this is really
just trading using one light right
>> that is it's just horizontal lines right
and
literally letting price communicate to
us where liquidity is. Right? So,
everybody, and we talked about this
briefly in the first episode, there's a
lot of people out there like to say
there's liquidity above every high and
low, right? Right then and there, the
the novice trader or the amateur trader
is going to think there's highs and
highs and lows all over my chart. What
do I do? Right? Am I going to sell above
this, buy below this? It's best, in my
opinion, to literally just let the
market communicate to you where the
liquidity is. And that's what I mean by
this point right here. This is the
market communicating to you that we can
we now have liquidity above these highs
once we engineer liquidity the first
step to the Da Vinci model.
>> And in regards to this, what's very very
interesting is, you know, when people
hear high reward to risk potential, and
you can see very clearly why that's the
case, because you're getting such an
optimum entry with an invalidation not
far away, uh, with such upside potential
in terms of where you're targeting.
What's incredible is a lot of people
when it comes to prop firms, they're
always like, "Oh, you know, got to risk
2%, 3%, pass fast, get big payouts." But
with this model, you could choose to do
that, right? And run the risk that you
have with prop firms in terms of like
gambling and overdoing it. But instead,
with this model, you could risk 0.5% to
0.75%
and still make 10,000, $20,000 in
payouts because of the asymmetric
setup when it comes to the reward to
risk. Um now what's the reality though
with that in terms of very briefly when
it comes to the entry do you have rules
around let's say if it doesn't work out
you know we're not sitting here saying
this is 100% strike rate right
>> so when it doesn't work out do you have
rules around you know if it's maybe
messing around the entry or it ends up
obviously invalidating the setup like
what sort of rules do you have in place
of maybe max tries or what does that
actually look like when it comes to you
know executing this
>> so okay from a risk perspective I I
always have and everybody's different I
have a specific amount a specific
specific figure I'm willing to risk on a
daily basis, of course. Now, from a
technical perspective, yeah, let's just
say, for example, and listen, like R
says, and nothing's 100% out there.
There's going to be times that the setup
is invalidated. Um, but I'm telling you,
actually, if you end up applying this
model correctly and waiting for the
higher probable ones, the win rate on
this specific model is um it's
incredible to say the least. Futures
traders, it's time to hear about Apex
Trader funding, the largest futures firm
in the industry. They have completely
changed the game with their new
evaluation. So far, they've already paid
out over $600 million to traders around
the world just like me and you. Now, not
only that, Apex actually holds the
record for the largest payout to
traders, which is of course with
Jadecap, no stranger to chart fanatics,
with $2.5 million in a single payout.
And the person before that was Trader
Kane with $2 million in payouts. Now,
what sets Apex apart? Apex, you can get
up to 20 accounts, which no other firm
offers. Now, not only that, they have
extremely clear rules with their revamp.
There's no MAE rule, no 5 to1
risk-to-reward rule, no hidden rules, no
gray areas, clearly defined draw down
models. So, you have two options now.
End of day draw down and intraday
trailing draw down, which means no
payout denials, no payout reviews, no
discretionary decisions, and no
surprises. What sets them apart as well?
traders receive 100% of approved payout
requests up to 20 accounts as I
mentioned and one day to pass. Now, the
other thing that I love about Apex is
not only can you get 20 accounts, but
there's different account sizes. So,
they have 20K accounts all the way to
150K accounts. So, you can get 20 of any
of the account sizes that you choose.
Not only that, you have various trading
platforms from Wealth Charts to Trade of
Rhythmic. The choice is yours. So, make
sure you use the code CF to get up to
90% off on evaluations right now using
the link in the description below. Trade
at Apex today. Let's get back to the
episode. And don't take my word for it.
Study the model and go look at the
charts and you guys will see exactly
what I mean. However, going back to like
an invalidation kind of look, let's just
say price comes down and sweeps out this
low, then I need to wait for something
like this to occur again, right? I need
to see early buyers induce in the
market. I need to see those early buyers
taken out and then I will look for my
entry again. And the reason why I'm
saying that is because we still have
liquid to the upside. Meaning, okay,
maybe we were early. That's fine. But it
does not mean the direction in the bias,
the idea is incorrect.
>> And just to be clear as well, this
entire model would just be flipped
upside down for a short.
>> Oh, 100%. Yeah, this this exact model
right here would literally just be
inverted. Um
Yeah. Yeah. There's going to be we're
going to look at bearish examples as
well just to train the eyes as much as
possible. But yeah, nothing changes.
That's the beauty of this model is
sometimes like and you know what there's
there's a perfect example we're going to
go through in the charts afterwards. But
sometimes I'll have like a Da Vinci
model on the higher time frames that's
providing me my direction, providing me
my bias, and then I'll have a Da Vinci
model playing out on the lower time
frames providing me my entry. And that's
why I feel like this model is like so
simple but so powerful because it it can
provide me my direction but it can also
provide me my entry right higher time
frames down to lower time frames and
that's when the RR can get stupid. Okay,
I don't want to spit out stupid numbers
but like I said don't take my word for
it. Go and look at the charts afterwards
and you guys will see exactly what I
mean and maybe you're going to be
trading live later as well. So if people
see it lies as well just before we move
on and start breaking down step by step
with the charts as well is you know we
know it's fractal so it doesn't mean
higher time frame to lower time frame
but generally for what you do uh what
time frame are you sort of operating
this on?
>> Uh great question. Um typically uh I I
trade both markets futures and uh forex
or CFD whatever you want to call it.
Typically CFD I'm holding trades
longterm because you're able to do that
right over the course of a couple days
maybe even a week's time. However, in
the futures market, you got to close
before market close. So, let's just use
the futures market for example.
Typically, we'll be looking at um a
model to take an entry off the 1 minute,
5 minute. So, be really deep into the
lower time frames and then targeting
those I would say mid higher time
frames. You can call it 15 minute, 1
hour levels. Um and then of course you
use CFDs where you can hold the trade to
these higher time higher time frame
targets without the restriction of
closing early because of time. M
sometimes I could have a a a Da Vinci
model playing out on the daily time
frame that takes days to play out,
right? Um but yeah, be taking the
entries sometimes. There's been times uh
I think we can even cover an example
that I was taking entries off the 1
hour, the 4 hour still with like a 1 to
10 RR. Um again, that's that's the
beauty of CFDs. You can hold it, right?
>> Cool. Uh so should we start breaking
down in steps then?
>> Yeah. So okay, let's uh let's clear up
the board. Okay. So now we'll draw out
um the Da Vinci model on a bearish
scenario. Right? So
I always draw the bullish ones. Now I
got to think about Right.
Okay. So we have a
level of liquid to the downside. Now
price ended up moving bullish and taking
out a old high from the left. Wherever
there is let's just say there's
something over there. So we take on an
old high from the left hand side. Now
you want to be looking for entries to
the downside. Okay. Now just like we
spoke about before, typically what will
happen is
you have a level of liquidity built for
us here, right? Low taken. You have a
high approaching previous highs and then
it sells off to the downside.
>> When it comes to that being a level of
liquidity for us, is there a specific
reasoning behind that versus say here or
that versus say here? Uh typically again
it's the the pattern of waiting for a
high to respect a previous high or in
the flip side a low respecting the low.
So if I could you don't want to screw
yourself over and think about it from a
pattern perspective meaning okay there's
a high left now you want to wait for
price to come above and sell here right
away. Now, you got to ask yourself, why
are you selling above that high? Right?
You want to make sure there is liquidity
above this high before selling because
typically what happens is you'll just
get a pullback and a continuation. Boom.
Trade invalidated. So, you need to make
sure again wait for the market to
communicate to you that there's
liquidity above this high. So,
we have the market again running trading
above an old high to the left hand side.
We get a reaction down. Then the market
starts printing internal I would call
it. Okay, high respecting high. Okay,
again I just said internal. I don't want
you guys to get too spunked by that.
It's very simple. You have a high
respecting previous high and we sold
off. Okay, now coming back down to the
downside. All right, we're going to talk
about this again just like you were on
the bullish example. Now we'll be a
bearish. So price is coming down to a
level of liquidity we've already
identified, right? We want to see price
trade below these lows eventually. Aka,
we want to sell into them. Right? Now,
typically what happens is you have
buyers looking for entries in this area.
Okay? And all of a sudden, you're
sitting there and you see the market
react. Okay? Now, I hope you guys are
all starting to see what I'm talking
about here. This is going to be now
known as our
engineered liquidity. Okay? You have
this low respecting liquidity from the
lefth hand side, respecting previous
lows and moving away telling us we are
engineering liquidity right here. Again,
first you can say it's first step. I
guess the first first step it this will
make more sense if you get if you watch
the previous episode is making sure
we're running something from the left
hand side. That's what actually
validates us looking for the sell of
course. So I guess you could say first
step taking out something from the lefth
hand side. Okay, in this example a high.
>> Mhm. Now the bearish setup is is
basically valid for us. We want to look
for those sells. Now the next step is
you want to see the market sell off to
the downside. Maybe induce some early
sellers. Perfect. And then here's the
engineer liquidity. Again, no engineer
liquidity, no model. If we have
engineered liquidity, then the model is
active.
>> Mhm. Okay. So from this point, we trade
above the high, we sell off to the
downside. We we create an internal
liquidity point. price continues selling
off and we engineer then you have the
move back up. Boom. High is taken out
and then lo and behold just like we
spoke about it on the um bullish example
markers here entry. Okay. And
stop loss. Okay. And then that's when
you get to capitalize on this whole move
to the downside targets here.
>> Exactly. And we're going to be targeting
the liquidity left at this low.
>> And then once that is taken does, you
know, obviously it depends on the setup,
depends on everything going on in the
markets, but general premise wise, once
that's taken, does that then open up
potentially this to then be the next
target?
>> Yes, of course. Let's just say for an
example here, we were overall on a on a
bigger perspective, we were bullish.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Okay. And this was essentially
what I would call a counterbias sell,
short-term sell. Yes. Then yeah, you
could typically look for a buy after
this low is taken. But I need everybody
to understand here, and this is
something I preach on a daily basis,
even on Turfanics Live, is we're not I'm
not a pattern-based trader. Meaning, if
you guys see this model playing out,
you're not automatically buying below
the lows in this example. You need to
make sure you always have a reason, a
logic for price to move to the upside.
Is there highs intact? Right? Maybe in
the past over here, whatever it is, is
there highs intact? Is there a reason
for price to run back up to the upside?
Going. All right. So, yeah, if we are
bullish overall, just to answer your
question simply, yeah, of course, there
maybe there could be a a buy scenario
below these lows.
>> Mhm. Cool. Should we go through it now
step by step on the charts? Yeah, of
course. Let's do it. 36 seconds. That's
Prime's fastest payout on record. Not 36
hours, not 36 minutes, 36 seconds. The
average payout time across the entire
firm is 34 minutes. and 98% of their
payouts clear in under an hour, which
has been verified by Deote. That's
exactly why they just won fastest payout
prop firm at the UF Awards. Most firms
make you wait weeks, and you still have
to pray and see if you'll get it. Ola
Prime CFDs pays you before your coffee
gets cold. And that's why you should
trade with Holar Prime for your CFD
accounts today. You can get a massive
30% off using the code CF at checkout.
So, make sure you go check them out with
the link in the description below. Now,
let's get back to the episode.
>> So, we're going to be hopping in on
gold. And actually, funnily enough, as
we're recording this, record highs on
gold. All right, I think we hit over
5,500. So, it's funny. We're going to go
over gold. And to be honest with you
guys, gold actually is my favorite asset
to trade. Um, unfortunately, we're
sitting in in times right now where it's
at $5,500 and it's just rocking to the
upside. And I'm not trying to buy that
high. Um, and I'm not trying to sell the
top, right? So, I'm simply waiting right
now. However, still setups to be looked
at um from relatively new price action.
Um and let's look right at this um
example right in front of us. So, first
of all, what we're going to identify
here is these highs. Okay. Now, from
this point, you can see how we printed
this high and we sold off to the
downside. Okay. That's very important
and that's what we were just talking
about the whiteboard. Okay. That would
be again probably what you could call
the first step to this model, right?
because in order for us to look for
buys, we need to of course be taking
something out from the left hand side.
So there's that old low that we were
talking about. Okay, perfect. From
there, you can see we get a short-term
pullback and then sell off again. Okay,
now bear with me here cuz this is
actually market open. So the price
action looks a bit iffy, but
nonetheless, we're going to go through
this and make it as pretty as possible.
Okay, right away I hope you guys can all
see why I grabbed this high from the
left-h hand side. Okay, look how we've
had this point here and this point here.
Respect previous highs. Okay, so again,
this goes back to what I was talking
about how I'm not guessing where
liquidity is, right? I'm not saying
there's liquidity above every high or
below every low. No, I'm literally I'm
literally letting the market communicate
to me that there is liquidity above
these highs. What do I mean by that?
This example right here, we have these
two swing points, these two highs
respecting this high from the left hand
side. Okay, it's very easy. From that
point, we sell off. Okay. Again, we grab
old lows. Perfect. From there,
price trades back up to the upside.
Okay. And you can see this was an old
low left actually right at market open.
Price comes back and sweeps it. Okay.
Now, if you guys again hopefully
hopefully you watched our first episode
of chartics, you guys would understand
that this would now be a low I would
view not to have liquidity. Okay. What
do I mean by that? It has simply swept
out previous lows. You can say this low
here and also lows over here and then
we've went bullish. Okay. So it's a it's
a low again I view to have no liquidity
which is important for me. Okay. Now
getting towards the most important part
of the model of the da Vinci model and
that's against identifying um the
engineer liquidity and I hopefully you
guys are starting to see this on your
own. That's the goal here. We're trying
to train the eyes as much as possible.
But you can see how these highs in the
lefth hand side, look at this equal
highs. Okay? And of course, just to make
this as easy as possible, we can
actually just grab all of this, right?
We've already identified that these
highs are going to be a future target
for us. Okay? Now, look what price does
here. Very important. We have this high.
We have this high respecting this whole
liquidity zone. These highs we've
already identified as a future target.
Again, very important. So what we can do
is we can literally just mark this on as
our engineered liquidity.
Okay, just like we were talking about
the on the um on the whiteboard. Very
important.
Coincidentally, look on the flip side.
We have left internal lows right here.
Now why did I mark out this low? Same
thing. We have this high again taken
out. Price goes bearish, respects this
lows and again goes bearishes again. low
gone bullish respecting previous lows.
I'm not predicting where price needs to
run to. I'm letting the market
communicate to me where price needs to
run to. I grab out these lows and drag
them across. Okay. So there you go. We
have engineered liquidity aka more
sellers entering the market here which
we are going to target and then we move
uh to the downside. We grab internal.
Perfect. Now how do we enter? How do we
participate participate in this move?
We need to identify this whole scenarios
again basically on the lower time
frames. Okay. So
sometimes what occurs is
you would take an entry here on the run
of liquidity just like we spoke about in
the diagram with our stop below this
low. Now in this example, we had a big
what I I call a liquidity block, a low
that doesn't hold any liquidity. So the
stop loss is too big. when the stop loss
is too big, the RR is shot in my opinion
and I just don't take those trades. So,
what I need to do is just wait for the
lower time frame to develop an entry for
me.
>> So, in this particular example to to
your point there, you have one nice
smooth view with the with the mouse, but
um the reason you mentioned that RR
being shot is because generally you're
mainly focused on targeting here, right?
>> Yes. which you know to some people one
to point one to 1.7 is is great but just
with this uh asset class and how it's
been even this trade would present
relatively a low risk to a high reward
that's outside the model in terms of
target wise even if you were to trail
even if you were to leave a runner fair
in this market it could work out quite
well uh but to your point obviously
following the model with the rules as we
want to, you know, as you said, this one
in particular has a larger stop. So,
some people might be okay with that, but
what do you do then otherwise if you
want to still take advantage of this?
>> So, and that's a great point. Everyone's
different at the end of the day. Some
people are comfortable taking a lower
RR, which to each their own. I always
say that for myself, I understand that I
perform the best. I make the the most
money when my RRS is minimum 1 to three
minimum. Um, and again, that's just
found what I worked. Again, everybody's
different. If 1 to 1.7 works for you,
hey, go ahead. But for myself, I do want
to see a higher R on the table. Now,
what do I do? I need to identify a
confirmationbased entry on the lower
time frames. Okay, so we're going to
dive into this price action right here.
Okay, so now we're on the one minute
chart. Um, and something I do want to
speak about quick is there's a lot of
stigma about the one minute chart. I'm
not not actually on the one minute chart
a whole lot, only typically in futures.
But this given example here on gold,
yes, the one minute time frame did
provide the entry, but I don't want you
guys to sit here being scared of the one
minute time frame. Sometimes it will
provide entries, sometimes it doesn't.
It's just you take it for what it is. In
this example, yes, the one minute did
provide us entry. So, we're going to
talk about this.
We grab the lows and this is literally a
da Vinci happening on the higher time
frames and then a da Vinci happening on
the lower time frames. This is like
textbook stuff. Beautiful. So, again, we
run an old low from the left. We are
bullish. We want to see price to the
upside. Okay. And remember the next step
is we want to identify early buyers.
Look low rand. Okay. Now look at this
price action. This very very choppy PA
on the way to the upside.
>> Okay. We have all of this liquidity to
the left.
Okay. And not only this is just lower
time frames. Bear in mind, don't forget
the higher, right? Remember this
engineer liquidity up here.
>> Yeah. So any bearish reactions deem them
to be false is what I call it and just
shortlived just pullbacks. Okay. So what
happens here and I'm going to mark this
on what I usually do is I mark it on as
a red box not an area I'd be trading
from. This is me understanding and I
hope you guys are seeing this that if we
react here this is now known as
engineered liquidity. Okay. So again now
there's a da Vinci forming in front of
us on the lower time frames. Okay. How
do we get involved? Remember this low,
deem it to not have liquidity. Okay,
this price action, all of this. Okay, if
you guys are good, I can't go any lower
than the one minute time frame, but if
you understand this price action, it is
simply just this. That's all it's doing.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. You can call it a channel, you
can call it structure, whatever it is,
it's building liquidity. Now, how do I
enter the market? You can see
from here, this level was respected,
which means there's going to be
liquidity below here. And watch this. We
run that last level of liquidity. Okay?
Not just this low, not just this low,
not this one, not this one, not this
one. If you trail your eyes all the way
to the extreme, it's going to be this
low down here. And remember, we view
this one, this last wick here, this last
area to not hold liquidity. Okay? And
this is just showing you guys the beauty
of high how high the RR can be.
Sometimes you have your entry as soon as
the low gets stabbed. Okay, nothing
else. As soon as it gets stabbed, stop
loss goes below the low. And of course,
this is going to be on a CFD chart.
Let's give it a little bit of breathing
room. Okay, stop loss goes below. This
is with breathing room. Bear that in
mind. And the target to the upside,
you're looking at a 1 to 12. And if I
just zoom out,
there you go. Okay. And again, the
beauty of this model is it happens on
the higher time frame. Okay. Look,
higher time frame for direction and then
it happens again on the lower time frame
for entry.
Okay.
>> And that's in a space of a few hours as
well. It's not even a
>> Yeah. I mean, look, if you an entry
right here at 10:00 a.m. exactly, and
target was hit in the afternoon. This is
Eastern St. um EST. Uh so you're looking
at two five hours and a possible one to
12 opportunity.
>> Okay.
>> But like just let's zoom in on the entry
uh where we chose our liquidity point
just to really highlight it because I
know we did it clearly on the the
whiteboard but this is the beauty of
what we try and do here is show the
picture perfect on the whiteboard but
then the reality. So it's good for us to
now see the reality of you know trying
to as you said train the eyes you know
especially on the lower time frames. Um,
so let's just like really zoom in on on
this entry point just to
100% be uh extra extra for that.
>> So yeah, this is the one minute time
frame. So again, I can't open it up any
lower than this. When we go into other
examples, you guys will see um this is
just the nature of price action.
Sometimes it it get I'm not going to go
into the seconds time frame. However, if
you guys are looking at this chart in
front of us right now, you can see that
we have a low printed, we move bullish.
Okay, price ends up coming back and
respecting this red box. So again, all
that is right here is literally just
that high taken, load respected. Very
simple. It's all fractal all the way
down to the 5-second if you want.
Unnecessary, but you guys know what I'm
getting at. And then after that, high
taken, low respecting low. So liquidity,
right? And then we move bullish, take
out a high, low respecting low. So I
hope you guys are starting to see where
I'm coming from, right? High taken, low
of respecting low, high ticket it, low
respecting low. So, it's just, guys, all
of this is a buildup. Mhm. Right. I've
got to tell you something. Hundreds of
thousands of traders have already made
the switch to Trade Zeala. And the
biggest reason, the AI. Tradezella is
the all-in-one platform built to turn
you into a profitable trader. And at the
center of it is an AI co-pilot that does
the heavy lifting for you. It watches
every session. It learns exactly how you
trade and your strengths and your
weaknesses, the patterns you keep
repeating without even knowing it. And
it tells you in plain language what's
working and what needs to change. The
moment you close a trade, your AI
captures it automatically. Fully synced
to your broker or prop firm. Zero manual
entry. You can replay any trade tick by
tick, pip by pip, to see the full
picture. Back test your strategy on
years of real data before you ever put
up real money behind it. Your AI
co-pilot ties all of it together,
surfacing insights you'd never find on
your own and guiding every decision you
make going forward. Hundreds of
thousands of traders, one AI powered
platform, real lasting results. Now, if
you want that AI co-pilot, and see your
trading excel, the link for Tradzella is
in the description below. Use the code
CF20 for 20% off your yearly
subscription or CF10 for 10% off your
monthly subscription. Let's get back to
the episode.
>> And you know what? Um, everybody's
comfortable with whatever it is. So,
what do I mean by that? Do you need the
absolute extreme? Check this out. Even
if you grab this load, for example,
okay, remember the stop loss is the most
important part. You need to make sure
your stop loss covers here. Don't get
greedy. Even if you didn't take the
lowest point, look at the RR still. You
are still catching a almost a one to
five. Okay? And that's not even the
lowest point. So even with a more
conservative entry, you're still looking
at almost a 1 to5 in 5 hours time. Okay.
Um but again,
>> bear in mind that was capping at the
high.
>> Yeah. Exact. Exactly. That's just
capping at the at the highs here. And of
course you keep looking even a 0.2 like
20% uh your runner of your original
position can do crazy numbers, right?
And sometimes can even be the same or
half or more than your original
position. Hundreds. You know the beauty
of having a high reward to risk ratio is
it allows for that because even if you
took majority of your volume off at one
to three some people do that right they
take off majority there but then that
partial if it goes 1 to 10 15 20 then
that normally that small partial is more
or if not the same as the original one
to three. So completely agree
>> but these elements that we're talking
about to your point that you said
earlier everyone has their own
personality. So some people will be, you
know, better off using a low risk
reward. Some will be better off using a
higher one. The beauty in this
particular model when making that
decision is really the win rate won't
change drastically. Normally high reward
to risk means low win rate, right? Um
but in this case because of these spe
specifics around the model and when
training the eyes and the patience has
been developed to wait for the model to
present itself before executing and then
of course the discipline to execute
according to the rules that low win rate
doesn't need to be there
>> right um which is incredible because
it's very rare to find uh you know that
high reward to risk ratio with a high
win rate but this is how it's done.
>> Yeah. my my honest truth about the in my
perspective on that whole scenario of um
the smaller the stop, the lower the RR.
In some ways, it's correct. However, in
my opinion, the reason that actually
occurs is typically for a higher RR to
occur, you need a lower time frame
entry. Now, what happens is people go
into lower time frames and they're
they're more prone to make mistakes.
That's just there's more price action,
there's more um time being shown to you
on the charts, so people are more prone
to make mistakes. when mistakes occur
lower our I mean uh the strike rate will
naturally go down. So that's my opinion
um and that's my perspective. However,
if you learn and prioritize patience and
discipline and focusing on the high
probable setups, your are your sorry
your strike rate won't get affected with
this higher model. And um in terms of
I'll ask towards the end actually this
question. Uh let's keep let's blast
through uh one sec but we got like 30
minutes so we'll blast through all.
>> Yeah, we'll go through we'll go through
another. Yeah, just blast through it.
We've uh Yeah, I don't like it. Perfect.
>> All right. So, now we're back on gold
again and I'm going to show you guys the
beauty of um basically proving to you
the model is
fractal again to all time frames. So, it
can go from the lower all the way to the
higher. So, this will be an example of
showing you guys even higher time frame
entries. Okay. So, again, we'll just
start. We can even just use the 15-minut
time frame just to see all this price
action right now. Um we can see how
price from the highs. So again this is
gold big selloff okay big big sell-off
and we have swept all types of lows from
the left hand side okay so any buyers in
the market here once price sells below
we understand that there is buyers that
trading here they've been trapped so
overall I do want to start seeing price
back up to the upside okay we left the
equals up here okay and then price
action actually in current PA all this
PA in front of us look at the amount of
liquidity we were building at the high
so we're going to briefly talk about all
that um the reason behind this long the
logic behind this long. Um, but we're
going to focus on again the model here,
the Da Vinci model. Okay, so what can we
see? And I always again I would like to
use red boxes here to kind of pinpoint
all of this. We have the market tapping
into this area once, twice. Look, then
we go long. Okay, we go long off an area
that had liquidity. Why did it have
liquidity? We have low respecting low.
Okay, and then we go long. Price comes
up to the high and builds liquidity.
Okay, so we have a level of liquidity
just like we drew on the whiteboard. We
have a level of liquidity we can look to
target eventually. Then price sells off
and we trade below an old low. Okay,
again nothing changes just like we were
talking about on the whiteboard. We
trade below this old low. Perfect. From
there we understand that there is
liquidity above here. We want to target
that. Okay. Now price runs these lows to
the left hand side. We go bullish.
This is going to be a trap area. We do
not want to be selling from these areas.
However, you can already see that we are
starting to get a da Vinci. Okay, since
we are respecting the highs, this would
be known as a engineered liquidity
point. So, we can just write quickly
engineered liquidity.
Perfect. And
we need to see early buyers in the
market, okay? In order for us to
capitalize on this buy back out to the
upside, we need to see early buyers. And
look what happens here. We have what I
would call a buildup of liquidity. Why
is this a buildup? Lows taken. Okay. And
then price comes up, takes the highs.
Why is this important? This is a common
retail pattern. Lows taken, highs taken,
which means people want to be buying
below the or sorry, buying above this
low. I view this low to have liquidity.
So, I want to buy below it. Okay, this
is stuff we touched on in the previous
episode, right? Okay, so if anybody is
kind of shaking a bit here, rewatch
previous episode or just watch it if you
haven't yet. Um, again though, low is
taken, which means early buyers are
trapped. We want to see that occur.
Coincidentally, we have a low to the
left hand side, okay, that we want to be
using as our basically a level to put
our stop loss. So, check this out. We're
going to have entry right at the low.
Okay, remember I'm always buy once the
liquidity is taken. I don't need to over
refine and find an imbalance in here.
Entry taken. Stop loss below the low and
target back at the highs. Remember,
we're not guessing where to target,
okay? The market communicate that to us
right here. High, respecting high. Okay?
So, that's going to be our overall
target. Okay? Don't get me wrong, you
have a bunch of internal, everyone's
different. You can if you're not
comfortable holding full volume, maybe
partial here, maybe partial up here,
right? You have a bunch of highs to the
left hand side to target. Okay? Now,
following along with this price action
because there's more than one entry here
and there's a lot to talk about. Not
going to spend a whole b bunch of time,
but there's some good stuff you guys
need to pay attention to. So, we move
bullish to the upside. Okay? And
remember,
any bearish reactions, deem them to be
false in a trap. This is now going to be
known as hope hopefully you guys are
starting to see this over and over,
engineered liquidity. Okay? We sell off
to the downside. Check this out. We trap
buyers. Anyone buying above this low,
they've been trapped. And look how price
rallies to the upside and grabs what?
The engineered liquidity. Okay, after
that's taken, price goes bearish. But
don't forget, guys, I can't stress this
enough. Don't forget our higher time
frame target here. So, if we do
beautiful stuff, beautiful stuff. If we
do react off this
engineer liquidity, Da Vinci model
intact. Okay, once we respect a move
away any whenever you find a buy
opportunity and I'm going to show you
guys exactly where it's going to be a Da
Vinci model and you want to be targeting
the highs. Okay, just like we're
initially were on this higher type or
sorry this uh this first entry here.
>> Okay, perfect. So, we sell off to the
downside. Okay, we start trading below
internal lows to the left. Okay, we grab
this low. We move bullish. Okay, from
there, check this out. We sell off. we
create some internal points. So we come
down, we respect something on the left
hand side and we move bullish. So same
scenario right here.
Okay, same scenario is happening right
here in front of our eyes. Okay, what do
I mean by that? Price incre it creates
all these internal points here and here
and then you get a bullish push up
taking out these highs. Why is that
important? We have just induced buyers.
It's a common retail concept of high
taken out, pullback, and they want to
buy this thing all the way up. Right? I
view that to the early buyers. I want to
see price below the low. Okay? And look,
coincidentally speaking, just like we've
been doing this whole time, you have
another low. I call it a liquidity
block. Um, we have another low that has
spiked out previous lows. So, I don't
view this low that needs to go. It
doesn't need to get ran. So, again, I
always buy once the lows are taken out.
>> Very simple. stop goes below this low
from the left hand side. Okay. And what
are we targeting? You guys already know
the answer to this. All the way back up
to the upside just like that. So you
have a possible 1 to 7 and 1/2 here and
you have another possible 1 to 7 right
here.
Okay. And again it's the beauty about
this is once you see it, you won't you
won't unsee it. But any bearish this is
very very important. Any bearish
reaction is engineer liquidity, right?
Look, it's the same thing happening over
and over. Okay? And then you get this
sell-off that provides, you can call it
like your discount or whatever.
>> I don't view it like that, but you get a
pullback induce early buyers and we trap
them. Boom. Take off to the upside.
>> Cuz the beauty is as long as the low and
the high of the model, so the low and
the high of what you're looking for
stays intact, the setup is valid. And
when you know which side is being
engineered, so in this case obviously to
the highs, you know, you're looking at
buyers. Yes. Right. And then so all you
have to do then because then okay that's
a relatively simple concept to follow
along and this is a very simple model.
However then as you say training the
eyes have patience because what a lot of
people would do if they're not using
this technique but they have a similar
structure in terms of targeting a high
and they want to buy low, right? They
might put a Fibonacci on, they might put
on a range on, they might have a general
premise of I want to buy below the 50%
at the minimum. Uh but then it's too
easy for them because that really leaves
still such an open window. Uh which
within there they'll probably have order
blocks, spare value gaps, inverted fair
value gaps, uh supply demand wherever so
many, right? And then that's why
sometimes people get the winning trade
but they lost three four times before
it. So then and the riskrewards probably
much larger or at least let's say one to
three. So they break even by the end of
it, right? After all that work. While
with this, you specifically have areas
of liquidity to just wait for. That's
it. And the hardest part for people is
literally just wait. And we've spoken
about the previous episodes. Sound like
a broken record, but if you don't see
liquidity, you are the liquidity. So
when big moves happen, you wait. You
wait for uh liquidity to get engineered,
things clear up, and you take entries.
And like just to show you guys the
common mistake traders make, you have a
high taken out here, right? And this is
going to be an area based off structure
that retail wants to take it long. Look
at the reaction it gives for retail to
go long, right? And then overall gives a
false reaction and boom, traps again.
This happens. High taken out, high taken
out. Price temporarily, and we'll zoom
in here.
price temporarily respects this and goes
long for
two three hours or two hours and then
boom you get the sell-off and we trap.
Okay, this is the entry. Okay, and it's
supported by this low from the left hand
side. So that's the important part here
guys. You guys can can see that every
entry is repeatable. Every entry is
systematic. The low here, that's where
the stop loss goes, right? The low here,
that's where the stop loss goes.
>> So now we're going to hop into So we
talked about gold. um showing you guys
that it it works in the forex market,
CFD market, the commodity, whatever you
want to call it. Now, we're going to
talk about NQ and how the Da Vinci model
can be used um in the futures market
because as we know, like I talked about
before, it happens across all markets.
All right. Um so, again, we're going to
be talking about NQ here. Start off on
the higher time frames. You can probably
already see where I'm heading to here.
Almost an exact duplicate of the the
whiteboard examples we were going
through, but price trades below an old
low from the left-hand side. Okay, now
that bullish idea is activated for us.
We want to be looking for those buys.
Okay, now if I open up this PA a little
bit for us.
Perfect. So you can see big selloff from
the highs. P my cursor coming down and
we sweep out lows from the left hand
side. Perfect. Now
check this out. Little possible extreme
entry. Not a da Vinci, but still
something to point out for you guys.
You have price coming down all the way
to this low and sweeping it, tapping
into an area that we have not tapped
into yet. Otherwise known as a low that
did not have liquidity. Okay. Now,
what's happening here is actually
happening right in front of our eyes as
well on the in the current idea, the
current price action. What do I mean by
that? Price has sweeped out a low, okay,
creating this low that we view not to
have liquidity. Okay. Now, in order for
us to take advantage of price back up to
the upside, we need to see price
engineer liquidity first, right? And
what do we have here? So, typically this
is actually just like a POI on the
higher time frames of retail, but this
whole area here, right, is an area that
sellers are going to be looking to take
maybe confirmation entry entries off of
or just entries as a whole, right? Maybe
here and then these whole areas here.
Okay? So what we can do is again we can
just mark this on just to make this easy
for you guys. Engineered liquidity.
Okay. Any reactions in this area deem
them to be false. Should be a pullback.
And we're going to participate in the
buys back up to the upside. Okay. We go
bearish. Now identify where buyers are
at. So we're going to open this up to
the 5m minute to make sense of this as
much as possible. Look to the left.
Okay. Hopefully you guys are starting to
see this here. High taken out. Okay.
price goes bearish, taps into this whole
area. Okay, and then back up to the
upside it goes. What does that now told
us? We have liquidity below these lows.
Okay, now this is when we were talking
about before. This is when patience is
incredibly important. Okay, if you don't
have patience and you don't trust where
the liquidity is, you're going to get
caught up in all of this kind of price
action. You're going to take unnecessary
L's. Okay, that's when the strike rate
gets affected. However, if you've
identified this level of liquidity, it's
very simple. Wait for it to get taken.
Okay, so this is an example, a great
example of showing you guys for the
people out there that can only trade the
higher time frames. For example, if you
guys are not able to be active on the
lower time frames, perfect example for
you guys. You have a level of liquidity
marked out here, aka early buyers, you
have a low down here that we can put our
stop loss. Perfect. So, this is what
it's going to start looking like. entry
would be right at the low just like
this. Stop loss is going to cover this
low from the left hand side. So again
for your higher time frame people out
there that can't be active limit simple
you set a limit at this liquidity point
this low stop loss goes below you don't
even need to look at the chart. Okay so
this is why I wanted to use this example
directly because show you guys that you
don't need to stare at the charts the
whole time. Okay so entry hopefully you
guys are starting to see where we can
target. You have equal highs left all
the way back up here. Okay? And you also
have these engineered liquidity highs on
the way back up, which could be used as
a partial point. All right? So again,
whatever you guys are comfortable, if
you guys can't hold one to five full
volume, by all means, you guys can
partial here, right? You're still
capturing almost a 1 to four, which is
great. Um because you as part of this
model and because of this way of
trading, you don't some people like take
partials just a riskreward point, right?
one to two, one to three, but you don't
do that.
>> No. And you know, it's something I've
I've talked about in the past. I'm not
the biggest fan of it. Typically, I
think I'm analyzing the chart for a
reason, right? I'm projecting possible
areas, levels that price could run to.
Why not take advantage of that analysis,
right? And like I told you guys before,
um if you guys do apply this model
correctly,
um these targets, these levels, they
they will get hit and they will get ran
to eventually, but they happen a lot.
Like the strike rate of it hitting these
areas is it's very high. Like I said,
don't take my word for it. Go into the
charts and identify. You guys will see
that. For example, once this low gets
taken, I know eventually this high will
go. And I'm very very confident in that.
Um, and it's something that maybe you
just lack a little bit of confidence,
but over over time, you guys will see if
you practice holding volume, um, I would
recommend removing that partially at 1
to three or that small RR and just hold
to those targets. That's when the
profits drastically increase. And that's
something that I did uh, a year, a year
and a half ago. Um, once I started
holding more volume, the profits did
increase. Right.
>> Right. Um and then again the only way
you can start stomaching that is
literally just doing it over and over,
right? Um but again, great example here.
You have multiple targets. You have this
engineered liquidity point just like we
talked about on the whiteboard. Very
important here. Okay. And then of course
you have the external highs being up
here. Okay. So again just based off your
guys have what you guys are comfortable
with. You have engineer liquidity highs
being a target and then the external
point. If I play this out, you guys can
see there's the entry trap in the early
buyers. You guys participate
and eventually
>> I say eventually.
>> Look, this is the reality of the market.
>> Yeah, there you go. This is NQ and it's
in Asia right now. So, typically price
won't move too much. But if we just bump
up a time frame, we'll speed this up a
bit. And there you was there any other
opportunities there? So, funnily enough,
actually, while the replay was playing
out, yes, there wasn't another
opportunity. You can see how we are.
What would we call this? Happy that you
pointed that out actually to make me.
>> Well, the funny thing is,
um, you know, people ask me about how I
trade because last year I did over
$100,000 in payouts past doing this.
That was on the side, more swing
trading, or at least like a bit longer
term. Uh, this year, well, January, I've
already done 20,000 in payouts. Um, and
I trade a lot of my thesis or foundation
around this from you.
>> That's awesome.
>> That's awesome. And I just sprinkle my
own stuff on there. And to be honest
with you, I should probably remove some
of my stuff because I think it just um,
you cogs or gets in the way.
>> Yeah, sometimes it's working out.
>> I mean, you had six figures in pays and
it's something's working.
>> Um, yeah. Send the hubs. All right. So,
here we go, guys. Same thing. We have
engineer liquidity at the highs, right?
If we sell off, um, again, it's just
simply telling us we have a reason for
price to push to the highs, right? Same
thing from this point, price moves
bearish, takes out an internal low. Same
thing occurs. Check this out. We have
highs taken, which induce buyers, and
then we come down and trap them. Okay,
what ends up happening here is we go
bullish again, taking out highs,
inducing buyers. Same thing, trapping
them. And I believe it comes all the way
down into what I call a
there you go a liquidity block. Okay, a
low that I view not to hold any
liquidity. So you could have taken and
look at the precision here. Sometimes it
boggles my mind to this day. You could
have taken a entry here.
Stop loss needs to go below the low to
the left hand side. This is always okay.
Now, extreme entry here and target, I
hope you guys can always see, is going
to be the high. So, this isn't the best
RR. However, listen, it's still great.
Yeah, sometimes 1 to three and a half
for people is is phenomenal. And don't
get me wrong, it it still is great to
this day. It's still a great R. Um, but
again, just showing you guys how every
single time the the Yeah, every single
time price respects the highs, it's
engineering liquidity, very important
for the Da Vinci model to be in play.
>> What do you do in terms of break even
for this model? you know what do do you
go break even at a certain point is the
do you leave it like what's your rule
set so yeah talking about managing
trades it's actually very simple very
straightforward for me and that's
another thing why this model is so
beautiful is it's just so repeatable so
systematic for myself where as soon as I
take this entry okay and price takes out
highs some sort of highs I understand
from a from the my system the persp the
perspective of my system that buyers are
induced some way so this high gets taken
out Okay, this point right here, let's
just say we're in this trade. We enter,
high gets taken out, I roll my stop to
break even. Okay, and I'm very extremely
confident in my target getting hit. Now,
does that mean it's going to hit 100% of
the time? No. There's going to be times
where I'm break even, and it is what it
is. However, I'm very confident in this
target getting hit. So, I'm going to
hold my full volume to this target.
Okay. Um, and yeah, that's that's
basically it. Be here. I typically will
hold majority volume to my targets. If I
do partial, I do partial very very
small. Right? So I'm talking 20 25% of
my uh position and I do strongly
recommend holding to those targets,
right? Those areas that you project
price to head to.
>> Gotcha. So just like I spoke about with
NQ, now we're going to hop into a Forex
example. Um I trade this market
actively. So, of course, uh this model
is um it works and it can be applied to
this this market. Uh this specific
example, we're going to go through U.J.
actually, funnily enough, a trade I just
took this week. Um and I realized 6600
and I still actually have partials. Just
funny enough, just like RZ was talking
about before, I still have partials
running to higher time frame targets
would could possibly bank me another
$5,000. So, it could be north of 11
grand. Um, we're going to have to see in
maybe in f future episodes if it plays
out, but um this comes out. Yeah, he
will slap it in there.
>> I did realize 6600s and it is a Da Vinci
trade and it's a bearish example. So,
it's going to be good for you guys to
see. Yeah. So, this is a good good trade
here. So,
>> we have uh again this is UJ and we're
going to start from the higher time
frames, work our way down to the lower.
We have highs taking out taken out on
the left hand side here. Okay. Ever
since then, we've been moving bearish.
Okay. And you guys can already see there
is a [__] ton of targets to the
downside. So I'm actually projecting
this thing to move quite heavily to the
downside. We'll have to wait and see if
there's more trade opportunities. But
nonetheless, the sell I took. So we sold
off big sell-off, but therefore there
was still
levels to the left-hand side I want
price to move to. Okay. And what do I
mean by that? If I zoom into this price
action, we can see
a level of liquidity built. Why do I say
this is a level of liquidity?
low high taken, highs taken, lows
respected, lows respected. So there's a
level of liquidity, right? That's all it
is. And I'm just identifying that and
understanding that that could be a
possible sell target for me. So if we go
to live price action, you can see the
cells played out. But let's talk about
the actual setup as a whole. Very
important stuff to cover here. So I'm
going to drag this over
now. All the low from the left hand side
here. Okay, we haven't taken it. We're
actually respecting it. So you guys
should already know what that means.
This low down here that we're starting
to print is known as engineered
liquidity. Okay, we are building
liquidity here. Okay, from there we
start moving bullish. And there's lots
of good things to talk about here. If
you look on the flip side and identify
where sellers have been entering,
hopefully you guys are starting to see
this, but we have been taking entries at
this high or sorry, we've been
respecting this high for quite a while
now, right? Why did I grab this point?
I've literally let the market
communicate to me to mark this high out.
I haven't predicted it. I haven't
guessed it. The market told me that this
high respected this high from the left.
So once it moves away, we have built
reasoning for price to push up there. We
have built liquidity. Whatever you guys
want to call it, we have a reason for
price to push above. Okay? And again,
you can see here respects it. Respects
it. Respects it spread. It taps into it
a bunch. So that tells me mark out this
high. I want to see price above it now.
After price takes it out, we're going to
look for sells. Okay. Now, how do we
participate in this sell back down? I
need to see what I would call a
liquidity block. Right? You guys all
know this by now. This is a high
that has taken out a previous high.
Okay? So, look, low taken, price comes
up, takes that high out, and we sell off
to the downside. Okay? So, this is going
to be an area. Remember, there's no
reason for price to take out
this point right here. So, I'm going to
use it to my advantage and take an entry
off of it. So, I mark out this whole
area. Now, my entry actually wasn't the
top. And the reason being was because I
set a limit. It was my bedtime and price
started playing out. It was my bedtime.
Um, price started playing out in London.
I live in Canada. I live in Toronto. So,
I'm not awake through 3:00 a.m. 4:00
a.m. This is Yeah, there was a time
unfortunately. That's a story for
another day. But, um, nonetheless, this
was a limit entry. Um, and this is the
beauty of taking higher time frame
entries sometimes. Um, and for myself,
you can do this in the CFD market
because you can hold it for a couple
days, right? So, I can take advantage of
that. So, entry. Now, check this out.
This is where a lot of people make the
mistake or make mistakes. There is a
[__] ton of liquidity to the downside,
right? And price has taken out highs,
comes down to the lows, this low
respecting here, and moving bullish. So,
we have built a ton of liquidity to the
downside. It is a great confluence for
us to see that because now price has a
reason to go lower. So again, here is
our engineered liquidity. Da Vinci
models intact. We take our entry here,
stop loss above. And now we're simply
just riding this down to where the low
from the left. Why? Cuz that is
engineered liquidity. And there you go.
Um 1 to five here. And yes, I'm looking
for further downside. But just to keep
it easy, simple and sweet for you guys,
you have this low here being the target
from the left hand side.
>> Amazing. Very, very simple, very
straightforward. Honestly,
>> the one question I had earlier that I
I'll come back to towards this
>> is training the eyes is like the the
theme throughout this episode like what
does that actually look like and mean to
you for the audience at home who want to
develop this? Cuz no doubt I imagine
pretty much everyone watching is going
to want to try and implement this in
some way. like what do they need to be
doing in order to train their eyes and
get that level of insight that you've
shown?
>> Yeah, that's that's a great question. Um
I think training the eyes is incredibly
important. U now what do I mean by that?
Um repetition and consistency. So that's
why we're me and RZ are sitting down and
going through a bunch of examples right
now and showing you how to apply this
model over and over and over. And what
that's what that's doing is it's
training your eyes. And the importance
behind that is if you train your eyes as
much as possible meaning you apply this
over and over and over and over. Now
when you go into the live markets
naturally you will start seeing the
model play out in front of your eyes
right however if you lack experience you
lack repetition you're not training the
eyes then how are you supposed to go to
a live market and identify this model in
lifetime right so that's why and I I use
that term actually a lot training the
eyes very important to because if you
don't um then you're going to struggle
to perform and you're going to struggle
to identify these setups in live
conditions right
>> that's true now links for Marco will be
in the description below. So, make sure
you check those out, drop him a message,
and thank him for the value that he has
dropped today. Uh, other episodes are on
screen. Talking of which, we'll link
Marco's previous episode. Even at this
point, he's already told you three, four
times if you haven't seen it, but we'll
do it one more time. Um, but make sure
you hit subscribe and until next time,
everyone, this has been Char Fanatics.
Take it.